<resources>
    <string name="app_name">ConflictWatcher</string>

    <string name="navigation_drawer_open">Open navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_close">Close navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="title_activity_conflict_syria">ConflictSyria</string>
    <string name="syria_text_1">
        The Syrian Civil war is a currently ongoing civil war fought in Syria between multiple sides. This conflict originated from the wide wave of Arab Spring protests in 2011. These protests grew out of dissatisfaction
        with the Syrian Government, and it has massively escalated after the Government violently suppressed the protests demanding removal of the president, Bashar Al-Assad. \n\n

        The conflict has been ongoing since early 2011, and is currently the second deadliest in the 21st century. This conflict is especially of importance due to the large number of outside actors that are investing military manpower,
        and financially supporting various factions. In effect, the Syrian Civil War is another proxy war with various countries around the world contributing to it.

    </string>
    <string name="syria_text_2">There are 4 main belligerents in this war, with each having various support from other countries: \n\n
         Syrian Arab Republic:\n Known as the Government &amp; Pro-Assad forces. They recognise Bashar Al-Assad and his government as the rightful leaders of Syria. Pro-Assad forces are fighting to preserve Assad as president,
        and claim the whole of Syria as theirs. Their main external supporters are Russia, Iran and various Shia Islamist groups. \n\n

        Rebel Forces:\n This comprises various groups that are against the Assad government. There are many organisations within this, such as moderate groups, and Sunni Jihadist groups such as Ahrar al-Sham and HTS(Hayat Tahrir Al-Sham).
        These groups believe in the establishment of a state based on a strict interpretation of Sunni Islam and claim to be religiously oppressed by the Assad Regime.\n
         Each of these rebel groups has various supporters including Turkey, Qatar, Saudi Arabia and The United States.\n\n

        Islamic State of Iraq and Levant: \n
        Known by its various names including ISIS, ISIL, Daesh or simply IS(Islamic State), is a militant group which follows a hard line salafi jihadist doctrine of Sunni Islam. They established an Islamic Caliphate during 2014
        and very notorious for their propaganda videos and actions against anyone it deemed to be their enemy. IS fought actively against every side in this war, even other Sunni jihadist groups. As of 2020 virtully all of their territory
        has been recaptured and they only operate as an underground terrorist organisation.\n
        The Islamic State doesn\'t have any official state support, but a large number of people moved to Syria and Iraq to fight for the group. \n\n


        Rojava: \n
        Rojava, or the SDF(Syrian Democratic Forces) is an alliance of primarily Kurdish, Arab and Syyrian militias, fighting to create a democratic and secular Syria. They primarily fought against IS, successfuly dirving them out of
        large parts of Syria, with the help of Coalition Forces. However, many groups are hostile towards them, including Turkey and Syrian Rebel groups. The SDF has not actively fought against the Syrian Government apart from minor clashes.\n
        Their main supporters are the CJTF-OIR, an international coalition including the USA, France and UK amongst many others.

    </string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>

    <string name="syria_text_3">The toll on human life in the war has been staggering. Since the beginning, an estimated 570,000 people have died as a result. The war is still seeing significant battles, as the month of January 2020
        saw 1,200 fatalities. There has also been a vast refugee crisis, with more than 6 million people internally displaced, and 5 million fleeing to other countries.\n\n

    The economy of the country has  been devastated  due to the war, also because of sanctions, such as from the US Government. While this is intended to impede the Syrian Government\'s power and authority, it can have a negative effect to
        the people of Syria. It can decrease their economic resources, and increase their reliance on the government.\n\n

    In 2018, the World Bank estimated that about half of the country\'s health and education facilities, and a third of it\'s housing stock has been destroyed by the conflict. An estimated $226 million in GDP has been lost due to the conflict,
        only between 2011 and 2016.
    </string>
    <string name="syria_text_4">As of 2020, there is still active fighting between the Government and rebels, and between the SDF and rebels and Turkey. There have been many initiatitives to broker a peacefire, but they either
        fail or do not last.\n\n

        However, with the Syrian Government and SDF controlling the majority of the country, and their relative neutrality against each other, there is a lack of active fighting in the majority of the country. The Government and SDF is
        currently in negotiation in order to reach a solution between the two entities.



    </string>

</resources>
